# LAURA TANNAHILL

#### **FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

☑ LNTannahill@gmail.com 📞 (902) 580-5085 👂 Halifax, NS

🕜 laurtann 🛚 in laura-tannahill 🔧 lauratannahill.com

#### SUMMARY

I am a driven and detail-oriented Full-Stack Developer transitioning from a background in television production and hospitality. While completing a diploma in Marketing Management in 2019, I discovered a passion for programming and all things marketing automation. I spent the last two years sharing the stories of tattoo artists and female innovators on television here in the Maritimes and across Canada - and I'm excited to continue sharing stories through great software.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, HTML & CSS

Frameworks & Libraries: NodeJS, ReactJS, Rails, Ajax, jQuery, Express, Bootstrap, Tachyons & Material UI Testing: RSpec, Storybook, Jest, Cypress, Mocha & Chai

Systems, CMS, Databases & Other: PostgreSQL, Active Record, Wordpress, Git, Figma, Heroku & Netlify

## **PROJECTS**

# Layers (7)

An app for music teachers and learners where users can isolate individual layers of their favourite songs and play or mute one or many. Learning the bass? Isolate just the bass track while you learn, or mute it so you can play along with the band. Demo login: email: mail@gmail.com, pw: password Tech Stack: React, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, Node, Express, WaveSurfer & Material UI.

## Scheduler (7)

An Interview Scheduler app where a user can book and manage an interview with an instructor. Tech Stack: React, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, Axios, WebSockets, Storybook, Jest & Cypress.

# Jungle 🔼

A mini e-commerce application with Stripe payments. Tech Stack: Ruby, Rails, Active Record, RSpec & Bootstrap.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Production Manager Garnan Productions Ltd., Halifax NS

2019 - 2021

- Managed production scheduling and worked collaboratively with film crew on deadline-driven documentary television shoots across Nova Scotia for locally and nationally syndicated series.
- Designed Wordpress website, managed social media accounts for all productions (receiving between 3000 and 13000 impressions per post) and ran social media marketing campaigns to increase brand awareness & viewership.

Server/Bartender The Brown Hound Public House, Halifax NS

2019 - 2020

• Exercised strong communication skills to provide prompt and engaging service to guests.

#### **EDUCATION**

Diploma in Full-Stack Web Development Lighthouse Labs

2020 - 2021

- Intensive 12-week program covering full-stack technologies and computer science fundamentals.
- Worked on team and solo projects and received one-on-one mentorship with industry professionals.

Ontario College Diploma in Marketing Management Fanshawe College, London ON President's List (4.17 GPA)

2019

• Designed and launched a 25-page Wordpress website for a live Non-Profit client over a six-week period.

Bachelor of Science in Chemistry Dalhousie University, Halifax NS

2009 - 2012